A Finding Aid to the W.G. Constable Papers, 1905-1983, bulk 1920-1976, in the Archives of American Art AAA.conswmgp
Archives of American Art
W.G. Constable papers
bulk 1920-1976
1905-1983
AAA.conswmgp
Archives of American Art
25.7 Linear feet
The papers of art historian and museum curator W.G. (William George) Constable measure 25.7 linear feet and date from 1905 to 1981, with the bulk of the material from 1920 to 1976. The papers include biographical material; professional and personal correspondence; extensive lectures, writings, and notes; exhibition and book research files; printed materials; and photographs, glass plate negatives, and slides. There is substantive correspondence related to Constable's participation in the American Defense Harvard Group and about the formation of the Roberts Commission, including correspondence with Ralph Perry, Hugh Hencken, Paul Sachs and George L. Stout. There are numerous official reports prepared by Constable after World War II for the U. S. Office of Military Government for Germany.
Constable, W. G., (William George), 1887-1976
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged as 10 series.
Series 1: Biographical Materials, 1905-1983 (1.2 linear feet; Box 1-2, OV 28)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1906-1981 (6.2 linear feet; Box 2-8, OV 28-29)
Series 3: Lectures, 1909-1963 (4.6 linear feet; Box 8-12)
Series 4: Writings and Notes, 1910-1974 (2 linear feet; Box 13-14)
Series 5: American Defense Harvard Group, 1942-1946 (0.6 linear feet; Box 15)
Series 6: Office of Military Government for Germany, 1947-1952 (0.3 linear feet; Box 15)
Series 7: Exhibition Files, 1930-1969 (1 linear foot; Box 15-16, OV 29)
Series 8: Research Files, 1922-1976 (7.5 linear feet; Box 16-24, OV 28-29)
Series 9: Printed Material, 1921-1977 (0.5 linear feet; Box 24)
Series 10: Photographic Materials, circa 1940-1960 (1.4 linear feet; Box 24-27, OV 28-29)
Biographical/Historical note
W. G. (William George) Constable (1887-1976) was a museum curator and art historian who worked in England and Boston.
Born in Derby, England, Constable studied for the bar at Cambridge University, but was encouraged to pursue art over law by the Lord Chancellor who told him that law would be too strenuous after a two year convalescence from gassing during World War I. For three years, he studied at the Slade School and the Bartlett School of Architecture. In 1923, he joined the National Gallery of London where he became the Assistant Director in 1929. In 1930, he accepted the first Director's position at the newly formed Courtauld Institute, where he worked to develop one of the first programs on art history. In 1938, Constable became Curator of Paintings at the Boston Museum of Fine Arts and worked there until his retirement in 1957.
Throughout his career as an arts administrator, Constable remained an accomplished lecturer and held appointments as the Slade Professor of Art at Cambridge (1933-1936), Ryerson Lecturer at Yale University (1940), and the Lowell Lecturer at the Lowell Insitute (1958). As a researcher and art historian, he published a steady stream of essays on European and American art connoisseurship, and authored over ten scholarly books, including The Painter's Workshop (1953), Richard Wilson (1953), and Canaletto (1962), the definitive work on the Venetian master.
Constable was a trusted arts advisor and, in this capacity, worked for the Wadsworth Atheneum from 1943-1945. He also worked closely with Lord Beaverbrook to establish the National Gallery of Canada and later consulted for Sotheby's and the U. S. Internal Revenue Service.
In the years leading to World War II, Constable served as an advisor to the American Defense Harvard Group and was later appointed to the Commission for the Protection of Artistic and Historic Monuments in Europe (the Roberts Commission) by President Roosevelt. The Roberts Commission was responsible for the establishment of the U. S. Army's Monuments, Fine Arts, and Archives section. After the war, Constable served the U.S. government as a member of a commission responsible for the recovery of looted art work and the evaluation of the state of the arts in Germany and Italy.
After his retirement from the Boston Museum, Constable continued to research and write, and also served as president of the International Institute of Conservation (1958-1960) and the Renaissance Society of America (1959-1961). From 1957 to 1966, he worked on behalf of Christie's auction house, where he met with prospective clients and provided preliminary valuations of private art works and collections.
On February 4, 1976, Constable died in Cambridge, Massachusetts from natural causes.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment. Glass plate negatives are housed separately and closed to researchers.
Existence and Location of Copies note
Portions of this collection are available on 35 mm microfilm reels 3060-3089 at Archives of American Art offices, and through interlibrary loan. Researchers should note that the arrangement of the papers as described in this finding aid does not reflect the microfilmed order of the papers. The microfilm does not represent the entire collection.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The papers of W.G. Constable were donated in multiple gifts from 1978 to 1979 and in 1987 to 1988 by his son Giles Constable. Additional material regarding Constable's research on Canaletto was donated by researcher J.G. Links in 1985.
Related Archival Materials note
The Archives also holds additional materials related to W.G. Constable, including an oral history interview with Constable conducted by Robert Brown in 1972-1973, and a photograph and clipping of Constable donated by Eleanor Barton in 1982.
Additional W.G. Constable papers are located at archival materials are also located at St. Johns College in Cambridge,England; the Warburg Institute in London, England; the National Gallery in London, England; and the Society for the Protection of Science and Learning in London, England. Photographs of works art collected by Constable are found at the British Studies Center at Yale University. Records relating to his tenure at the Museum of Fine Arts, Boston are housed there.
Scope and Contents note
The papers of art historian and museum curator W.G. (William George) Constable measure 25.7 linear feet and date from 1905 to 1981, with the bulk of the material from 1920 to 1976. The papers include biographical material; professional and personal correspondence; extensive lectures, writings, and notes; exhibition and book research files; printed materials; and photographs, glass plate negatives, and slides. There is substantive correspondence related to Constable's participation in the American Defense Harvard Group and about the formation of the Roberts Commission, including correspondence with Ralph Perry, Hugh Hencken, Paul Sachs and George L. Stout. There are numerous official reports prepared by Constable after World War II for the U. S. Office of Military Government for Germany.
Biographical material includes W.G. Constable's curriculum vitae; club memberships; personal, educational, and military records; three memorial essays and obituaries; five address books; appointment books dating from 1930-1968; and financial records related to personal business travels.
Correspondence is mostly professional and arranged into General, Committee, Condolences, and J.G. Links. General correspondence is with friends, business associates, auction houses, galleries, and museums. The letters cover a wide variety of professional work, such as research projects, letters of inquiry and recommendation, and work done for Christie's and the Internal Revenue Service. Correspondents include Mortimer Brandt, Helen Frick, Helen Gluck, William Ivins, Duncan Phillips, Paul Sachs, and Rudolph Vasalle, among many others.
Committee related correspondence includes letters, memoranda, and reports related to ongoing committee objectives, projects, and routine activities. There is correspondence related to Constable's advisory work with the Art Gallery of Toronto, the National Gallery of Canada, and the Watts Gallery, among other projects. Condolences consists of letters and cards received by Constable's wife, Olivia, after Constable's death. Correspondence with J.G. Links is primarily about the second edition revision of Constable's book Canaletto.
There are over 170 drafts of Constable's notes and outlines for lectures. Topics range from 13th-20th century European and American art to museum conservation, ethics, art education, and art collecting. The series also includes lecture notes from organized touring trips to Canada, Northern Europe, Scandanavia, and Poland.
Writings consist of Constable's published and unpublished articles, articles submitted for the Encyclopedia of World Art, essays, notes, exhibition catalogs, translations, and drafts and research material related to Art Collecting in the United States, Art History and Connoisseurship, and The Painter's Workshop.
Files specifically documenting Constable's advisory role in the World War II American Defense Harvard Group drafting and organizing lists of men with curatorial, museum conservation, or library/archives backgrounds to aid in the protection European most valued cultural artifacts, artwork, and architecture. There are letters documenting the formation of the Harvard Group and its goals and objections. The files also include many of the original lists that were forwarded to the Commission for the Protection and Salvage of Artistic and Historic Monuments in Europe, also known as the Roberts Commission, eventually leading to the formation of the U.S. Army's Monuments, Fine Arts, and Archives division. The series also includes the Harvard Group's manual Safeguarding and Conserving Cultural Materials in the Field, committee minutes, and clippings related to their work. Correspondents include Ralph Perry, Paul Sachs, George L. Stout, and Hugh Hencken.
Constable's work after the war for the U.S. Office of Military Government for Germany is documented through numerous reports, memoranda, letters, and other official documents from the U. S. Army to Constable about surveying the state of German and Italian art institutions after World War II. The series also includes Constable's notebook "Visits in Germany" (1949), and a copy of his report Art and Reorientation: Status and Future of Museums and the Teaching of Art in Western Germany.
Exhibition files contain correspondence, notes, lists, research material, and reports related to exhibitions that Constable organized prior to his employment by and after his retirement from the Boston Museum of Art.
Research files contain materials relevant to Constable's interests and include notes, lists, correspondence, and printed and photographic reference material. These subject areas cover artists, including extensive files on Canaletto and other vedute painters, museum conservation, museums and galleries, private and public art collections, and schools of art.
Printed materials include clippings, programs, book excerpts and other miscellaneous printed materials.
Photographic materials include prints of Constable with friends and family, as well as prints, glass negatives and slides of artwork. There are also prints of the Fogg Art Museum's interiors and exterior and interior shots of Tennessee Valley Authority dam projects.
Allied Forces. Supreme Headquarters. Monuments, Fine Arts and Archives Section.; American Commission for the Protection and Salvage of Artistic and Historic Monuments in War Areas.; Art Gallery of Toronto.; Brandt, Mortimer; Canaletto, 1697-1768; Frick, Helen Clay, 1888-1984; Germany (Territory under Allied occupation, 1945-1955: U.S. Zone).. Office of Military Government.; Gluck, Helen; Hencken, Hugh O'Neill; Ivins, William Mills, Jr., 1881-1961; Links, J. G.; Museum of Fine Arts, Boston.; National Gallery of Canada.; Perry, Ralph; Phillips, Duncan, 1886-1966; Sachs, Paul J. (Paul Joseph), 1878-1965; Stout, George L. (George Leslie); United States.. Internal Revenue Service.; Vasalle, Rudolph; Watts Gallery.; Art historians--England; Art historians--Massachusetts--Boston; Art--Conservation and restoration; Cultural property--conservation and restoration--Germany; Cultural property--Conservation and restoration--Italy; Germany (Territory under Allied occupation, 1945-1955); Museum curators--England; Museum curators--Massachusetts--Boston; Photographs; World War, 1939-1945--Art and the war; World war, 1939-1945--Destruction and pillage--Germany; World war, 1939-1945--Destruction and pillage--Italy
- Biographical Materials, 1905-1983; Series 1; 1.2 Linear feet Box 1-2, OV 28
  Scope and Contents note
  This series includes W.G. Constable's curriculum vitae, club memberships, and personal, educational, and military records, including passports, university exams and degrees, and a hair sample. The series also includes obituaries and three memorial essays written by friends and family; five address books; daily appointment books dating from 1930-1968; and financial records related to personal business travels.
  - Club Memberships, A-D, circa 1930-1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Club Memberships, D-O, circa 1930-1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Club Memberships, P-So, circa 1930-1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Club Memberships, Sp-Z, circa 1930-1950 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Curriculum Vitae, circa 1950-1960 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Employment Records, 1920-1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Essay, "Tribute to W.G. Constable" by Walter Muir Whitehall, circa 1976 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Essay, "W.G. Constable" by Gardner Cox, circa 1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Essay, "W.G. Constable" by Giles Constable, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Examinations, Bar (Law), 1914 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Oversized material housed in Box 28, Folder 1.
  - Examinations, University, 1905-1910 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Hair Sample, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Memorandum of Agreement (Contracts), 1927-1953 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Military Service Documents, 1916-1919 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Obituary, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Passports, 1933-1972 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - University Degrees, 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Address Book, Great Britain, circa 1930-1960 (Box 1, Folder 18-19)
  - Address Book, Europe, circa 1930-1960 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Address Book, North America, circa 1930-1960 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Address Book, North America, circa 1940-1960 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Address Memorandum, circa 1930-1960 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Appointment Books, 1930-1935 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Appointment Books, 1930-1952 (Box 1, Folder 24-28)
  - Appointment Books, 1953-1968 (Box 1, Folder 29-32)
  - Expense Books, 1906-1958 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Financial Records, circa 1930-1960 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Financial Records, 1936-1954 (Box 2, Folder 3-6)
  - Financial Records, 1956-1983 (Box 2, Folder 7-9)
  - Oversize Legal Examination Certificate, 1914 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    Oversized material from Box 1, Folder 10.
  - Oversize Military Certificate, 1915 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    Oversized material from Box 1, Folder 14.
- Correspondence, 1906-1981; Series 2; 6.2 Linear feet Box 2-8, OV 28-29
  Correspondence is primarily with Constable's friends and business associates discussing personal research projects, professional and committee related work, and letters of condolences.
  Arrangement note
  The series is arranged as 4 subseries:
  2.1: General, 1906-1975
  2.2: Committees, 1924-1976
  2.3: Condolences, 1976-1979
  2.4: J.G. Links, 1964-1981
  - General, 1906-1975; 2.1
    Correspondence includes letters to friends and business associates discussing personal scholarly research, book projects, museum conservation techniques, letters of inquiry and recommendation, general appraisel requests, and work done for Christie's and the Internal Revenue Service. Correspondents of note include Helen Frick, Duncan Phillips, and Paul Sachs.
    - A Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Agnew, Doreen, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Alford, John, 1958-1969 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - American Federation of Arts, 1957-1973 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Ames, Winslow, 1958-1966 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Apollo Magazine, 1957-1968 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Art Gallery of Toronto, 1959-1965 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Athenaeum, London, 1937-1975 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Ba-Bn Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Bo-Bz Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Bacon, T.W., 1940-1950 (Box 2, Folder 20-21)
    - Baltimore Museum of Art, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Beacon Press, 1960-1965 (Box 2, Folder 23-24)
    - Berger, Milton, 1959-1965 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Bernard, Herbert C., 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Bolton, Guy, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Bowdain College Museum of Art, 1963-1966 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Bradner, Leicester, 1949-1953 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Brandt, Mortimer, 1955-1968 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - British Council, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - British Foreign Office, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Burlington Magazine, 1923-1969 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Butler, Beatrice, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - C Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Cambridgeshire Education Committee, 1935-1936 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Canadian Art, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Cannon, Foster, 1962-1964 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Centner, Charles W., 1962 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Christie's (Christie, Manson and Woods Ltd.), 1945-1947 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Christie's (Christie, Manson and Woods Ltd.), 1958 (Box 2, Folder 41-44)
    - Christie's (Christie, Manson and Woods Ltd.), 1959 (Box 2, Folder 45-47)
    - Christie's (Christie, Manson and Woods Ltd.), 1959 (Box 3, Folder 1-5)
    - Christie's (Christie, Manson and Woods Ltd.), 1960-1962 (Box 3, Folder 6-10)
    - Christie's (Christie, Manson and Woods Ltd.), 1963-1967 (Box 3, Folder 11-14)
    - City of Auckland Art Gallery, 1958-1968 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - College Art Association of America, 1957-1963 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Courtould Institute of Art, 1930-1959 (Box 3, Folder 17-18)
    - D Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - De Beer Fine Art Ltd., 1966 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Dedham Vale Society, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Detroit City of Fine Arts, 1961-1969 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Drysdale, Susan, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Duncan, Louis G., 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - E Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Eastman Kodak Company, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - F Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Fitzwilliam Museum, 1937, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Fogg Art Museum (Coolidge, John), 1957-1967 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - French and Company, 1960-1964 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Frick, Helen C., 1947-1962 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Funke, Mary-Louise, 1966-1969 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - G Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Gainsborough's House Society, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Gallery of Modern Art (Ames, Winslow), 1959-1961 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Gillick, Mary, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Gluck, Helen, 1956-1969 (Box 3, Folder 37-39)
    - Goldsmith's Hall, 1958-1962 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Green, John, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Greene, B.M., 1958-1969 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - H Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Handford, Hubert E., 1958-1960 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Harris, Paul S., 1967-1971 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Harvard University, 1940-1957 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Hayes, John, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Hemp, W.J., 1958-1963 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Houghton, G.F., 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Howard Young Galleries, Inc., 1956 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Hutton, Edward, 1961-1969 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - I Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - International Institute for Conservation of Historic and Artistic Works, 1966-1969 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Ivins, William, 1944-1958 (Box 3, Folder 54-55)
    - Ivins, Barbara, 1961-1963 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - J Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - J.B. Speed Art Museum, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - K Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Keck, Caroline, 1961-1968 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Korchnoy, E.A., 1963 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Korf, K. Frank, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - L Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Leggatt Brothers, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Leverhulme Research Fellowships, 1937-1938 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Lewis, Lesley, 1966-1968 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Links, J.G., 1969 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Little and Ives Co., 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - M Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Malden Public Library, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Marconi, Bohdan, 1960-1965 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Martin, Mrs. Vincent, 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - McCormick, Thomas J., 1962 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1942-1968 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Mitchell, John, 1958-1968 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Montreal Museum of Fine Arts, 1959-1963 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Muensterberg, Helene, 1965-1967 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Mugar, Stephen P., 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Muller, Robert, 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 1959-1974 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - N Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - National Buildings Record, London (Godfrey, Walter), 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - National Gallery, London, 1929-1968 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - National Gallery of Canada, Ottawa, 1958-1969 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Nichol, E.G., 1959 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - North Carolina Museum of Art, 1960-1964 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - O Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Oxford University Press, 1954-1965 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - P Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Pantzer, Kurt F., 1958-1964 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Parsons, E., 1960-1964 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Phillips, Duncan, 1940-1964 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Pignatti, Terisio, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Pilkington, Vere, 1965-1968 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Poole, E.E., 1960-1965 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Pulitzer, Henry F., 1964-1967 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Q-R Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - R. Sovrintendenza Alle Gallerie, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Randall, Alec, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Rawlins, Ian, 1953-1962 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Rizzi, Aldo, 1964-1967 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Rosenberg, James, 1959-1961 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Rowley, Joshua, 1964-1968 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Sa-Sh Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Si-Sz Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Sabin, Herbert H., 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Sabin, Herbert H., 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Sachs, Paul, 1939-1965 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Sanborn, Ashton, 1945-1971 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Scrutton, Hugh, 1957-1963 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Sewter, A.C., 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Slade Professorship, University of Cambridge, 1934-1937 (Box 4, Folder 55-56)
    - Smart, Alastair, 1965-1968 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Smith College, 1947-1964 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Society of Antiquaries, 1942-1971 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Society of Dilettanti, 1936-1950 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Society of Painters in Tempura, 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - St. John's College, University of Cambridge, 1906-1911 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Stockwell, David, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Sulgrave Manor Board, 1957-1959 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - T Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Tavern Club of Boston, 1942-1957 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Thomas Nelson and Sons, 1960-1968 (Box 4, Folder 67)